<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<faq xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/">
  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Why is it called ScummVM - what does this name mean?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		<quote>Scumm</quote> comes from the fact that it was originally designed to run SCUMM games, like
		Monkey Island.
		<quote>VM</quote> stands for Virtual Machine.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		Every now and then somebody will raise the subject of finding
		a <quote>better</quote> name for ScummVM, one that fits better with its modern
		scope (which extends well beyond SCUMM games). So
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/ScummVM_Name">at this page</ulink>
		we present you with some nice alternatives. Choose whichever suits you
		best -- but we will stay ScummVM.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>What is SCUMM?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		SCUMM stands for "Script Creation Utility for Maniac Mansion". It is a
		utility used to create the famous LucasArts adventure games.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		It was initially created in 1987 by Aric Wilmunder and Ron Gilbert for
		the game "Maniac Mansion" and was used later, with some modifications,
		for Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders. Development on the SCUMM
		system continued for some time, and was used in Loom, Indiana Jones and
		the Last Crusade, Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis, Monkey Island
		1,2,3, Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road, Day of the Tentacle, The Dig and Full
		Throttle.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Is ScummVM free?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		ScummVM is released under the <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/gpl-2.0.html">GPL (General Public
		License)</ulink>, so it's more than free. ScummVM source code is freely
		available and you can do whatever you want with it. If you make
		modifications to it and redistribute your work you MUST make the source
		available. However, the ScummVM team would be pleased if you choose to
		send them your modifications, so they can be merged into the main tree.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Where do I find ScummVM?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		You can find it on the download section on our <ulink url="/">web site</ulink>.
		You can download the latest version, which could be a little old. For the most
		recent cutting-edge in-development version, you have to compile it yourself from
		the repository or use the precompiled 'daily builds' linked from our download page.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.compiling</href>
      <question>How do I compile the source code for my OS?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		The source code package contains a file called
		<ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		explaining the basics. More detailed information can be found
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/Compiling_ScummVM">on our Wiki</ulink>.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.supported-platforms</href>
      <question>On what platform does ScummVM run?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		ScummVM should be able to be compiled for any platform supported by
		<ulink url="http://www.libsdl.org">SDL</ulink>, with just small modifications.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		ScummVM runs on a wide variety of platforms, including Win32 (Windows
		95/98/ME/NT/2000/XP/7/8/10), Linux i386 and PPC, OS X, many smart phones
		and game consoles and more. It is also part of various BSD ports
		collections and included in Debian testing and unstable.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		For a more comprehensive overview please take a look at the
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/Platforms">platforms list</ulink>
		in our Wiki.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.make-new-games</href>
      <question>Can I use ScummVM to make new games?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		A few engines supported by ScummVM have publicly available authoring tools. Developing for any other
		engine would require the author to develop their own tools, which is not a trivial task as a full
		understanding or specification for the engine would be needed. The engines which are known to support
		authoring tools and thus currently have a number of "fangames" also have detectors which will detect
		and add entries for unknown games, though upon game completion contacting the ScummVM team will allow
		a full detection entry to be added of the stable final version. You could for example use
		the <ulink url="http://dead-code.org/">Wintermute</ulink> Development Kit.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		It should be noted that other non-ScummVM supported systems for Point and Click game development exist,
		and the authoring tools for these may be easier to use and more suited to your game.
		<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adventure_Game_Studio">Adventure Game Studio</ulink> is probably
		the most popular and supported system with tools and a large developer community.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		You will find more information on this topic and a more comprehensive list of authoring tools on
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/HOWTO-Fangames">our wiki HOWTO-Fangames page</ulink>.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Supported games</title>
    <entry>
      <href>question.supported-games</href>
      <question>What games does ScummVM support?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		We have a <ulink url="/compatibility/">compatibility
		list</ulink> on our website that contains an up to date list of which
		games work, and how well they work. Apart from SCUMM games, we now
		also support quite a few other adventure games. More games may
		be added, but this is not a common occurrence &#8212; see below.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.add-new-games</href>
      <question>Will ScummVM support other games?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		That depends on several factors: First off, it has to fit within the
		scope of ScummVM, i.e., it has to be a point and click adventure with 2D
		graphics. Secondly, there must be a developer (or multiple) who is
		interested in working on this and both willing and able to carry out the
		required work.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		You have to understand that all ScummVM developers are volunteers who
		work on ScummVM in their spare time, solely for fun, and not for profit.
		Yet reverse engineering a completely new game without source is a long
		and difficult process. Even with source it can be very tedious and time
		consuming.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		So unless you work for a company interested in providing us with source
		code for one of your classic titles, or want to do the work yourself,
		please do not ask us to add support for a new game. We will simply
		reject any such requests out of hand.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>When will Maniac Mansion Deluxe be supported?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		The short answer: not anytime soon. The long answer:
		This game is a fan-made replica of the original Maniac Mansion. It is not the same
		game as Maniac Mansion Enhanced, which we do support. It features improved
		music, sound, 256-colors graphics and reworked game interface. It was made using
		the <ulink url="http://www.adventuregamestudio.co.uk/">Adventure Game Studio</ulink> which
		is a free, and now open-source graphics adventures engine. There are Windows,
		Linux and FreeBSD versions of the engine. This engine is not currently supported by ScummVM
		and a lot of work would be required to support it.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Will you add support for Sierra's SCI games?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		FreeSCI has now been merged into ScummVM, see <ulink url="/news/20090215/">this news item</ulink>.
		However, many SCI games are still not supported, so you may also want to check out <ulink url="http://www.dosbox.com">DOSBox</ulink>
		if you want to play all SCI games, especially newer ones.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Running games</title>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>How do I install games to run in ScummVM?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		For most games you do not need to run the installer. Simply copy
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/Datafiles">the files listed here</ulink>
		from your floppy or CD to your hard drive, then start ScummVM. Click
		on 'Add Game' and select the directory to which you copied the game
		files.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		For some games the files are packed and not directly accessible
		on the floppy or CD. In such a case you will need to run the original
		game installer and then copy the files from where they have been
		installed to the directory in which you want to install the
		game to play with ScummVM.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		For Macintosh games, see also "<xref linkend="question.mac-games" endterm="question.mac-games.text"/>".
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Do I need original CD or Floppy disks?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		It depends. These days number of companies such as <ulink url="http://www.gog.com/?pp=22d200f8670dbdb3e253a90eee5098477c95c23d">GOG.com</ulink>
		legally distribute DRM-free versions of old games, but not every game supported
		by ScummVM is available there. In such cases you will most probably need the original media.
		ScummVM won't work without them. If you would like to
		buy these games, we suggest you refer to our <ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/Where_to_get_the_games">Where to Get the Games</ulink>
		Wiki page.
		Do not ask the ScummVM team where you can download the full versions of
		LucasArts games. These requests will be ignored or you will be directed to the aforementioned
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/Where_to_get_the_games#LucasArts_Games">wiki page</ulink>.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Does ScummVM work with all versions of games?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		See "<xref linkend="question.supported-games" endterm="question.supported-games.text"/>".
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Can I play through xxx (place your favorite adventure game here) ?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		See "<xref linkend="question.supported-games" endterm="question.supported-games.text"/>".
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Can I save/restore the game?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Yes. Saving and restoring is supported. In most games you can use Ctrl-F5 to display the Global ScummVM Menu
		and get access to saving and loading functionalities. Some engines may have different or additional ways to
		save and restore games (for example in SCUMM games you can use Alt-1/9 to save, Ctrl-1/9 to restore, or
		F5 to access the save/load menu). See the <ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		for more info.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Do savegames from the original games work in ScummVM?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		In general, no. We do not have any plans to load old savegames (with the exception of the
		Simon the Sorcerer series of games). Newer versions of ScummVM have
		also sometimes broken compatibility with older ScummVM savegames. Since ScummVM is
		under heavy development, this may occur again in the future.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Graphics and Audio</title>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Does ScummVM support CD audio?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Yes, ScummVM fully supports CD audio in Gobliins (CD), Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade (FM-TOWNS),
		Loom (CD &amp; FM-TOWNS), Monkey Island 1 (CD, FM-TOWNS &amp; SegaCD) and Zak McKracken (FM-TOWNS). Just keep your game CD
		inserted into your CD drive when you start ScummVM. If you have more than one CD drive in your
		system, you can specify your CD drive using the -c command line parameter. See the
		<ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		for more info.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Does ScummVM support using MP3/Ogg/FLAC files instead of CD audio?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Yes. You can use LAME or some other CD audio conversion utility to convert your CD audio to MP3. Since
		version 0.3.0 we also support Ogg Vorbis files, and FLAC is supported since version 0.7.0. See the
		<ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		for more info.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Does ScummVM support using MP3/Ogg/FLAC files instead of the original MIDI music?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		In general, no. If all the game does is to play or loop a tune it would be possible, but many of the games do
		fancy stuff like smooth transitions from one tune to another, or turn individual instruments on and
		off, etc. There's simply no way ScummVM could take a piece of digital music and emulate that kind
		of behavior.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		This question usually comes up in connection with Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road (which has a few
		unused bonus audio tracks on the CD) and Monkey Island 2 (which is sometimes distributed on
		the same CD as the version of Monkey Island 1 that uses CD audio). Both of these games do far
		too much fancy stuff to even consider an idea like this.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		However for a few other games we do support using MP3/Ogg/FLAC files instead of the original MIDI music.
		See the <ulink url="http://www.jameswoodcock.co.uk/content/scummvm-music-enhancement-project/">ScummVM Music Enhancement Project</ulink>
		web page for a list of games that supports such a feature and get access to the recorded music files.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Does ScummVM support filtered graphic modes?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Yes, ScummVM supports several filtered graphic modes such as AdvMAME2x, also known as
		<ulink url="http://scale2x.sourceforge.net/">Scale2x</ulink>.
		See the
		<ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		for more info and <ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/User_Manual/Appendix:_Graphic_filters">our wiki</ulink>
		for a comparison of the available filters.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Can I run my game full screen?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Yes. You can either start your game using the -f command line parameter, setting
		the game to Full Screen in the ScummVM Options dialog, or by using the Alt+Enter key
		combination in-game to switch between full screen and windowed modes.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Troubleshooting</title>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>My game won't run.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		First make sure your game is supported.
		See "<xref linkend="question.supported-games" endterm="question.supported-games.text"/>".
		If it is a supported game and you
		have followed the instructions in
		<ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		to the letter, then see "<xref linkend="question.report-bugs" endterm="question.report-bugs.text"/>"
		to report this as a bug.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>I installed my game but ScummVM can't find it.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		First don't use the install.exe or setup.exe shipped with the game. They usually will
		not do what you need to run the game with ScummVM -- rather they just copy the game
		.exe and install some shortcuts. ScummVM requires all game
		data to run, so you will need to copy those manually. Look at the
		<ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/Datafiles">Game Data Files</ulink> page for
		further details.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.no-sound</href>
      <question>I don't hear any sound.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Check the <ulink url="/compatibility/">compatibility list</ulink>
		to see if your game has sound support currently. You can
		also try the -s command line parameter to set the in game SFX volume.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>I don't hear any music.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		See "<xref linkend="question.no-sound" endterm="question.no-sound.text"/>".
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>My game crashes at some point.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Check the <ulink url="/compatibility/">Compatibility List</ulink> to see if your game has any known issues. If you can
		reproduce this crash more than once, please report it to our Bug Tracker.
		See "<xref linkend="question.report-bugs" endterm="question.report-bugs.text"/>".
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		If you are experiencing random crashes, and your game plays music from
		CD, you most certainly have encountered a Windows bug. Try copying the data files from
		CD to your hard disk, and running them from there.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>ScummVM crashes, but the console window disappears too quickly to see the error message.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		On Windows, to make it visible, you should run ScummVM from the command line. To open a
		command prompt, open the Start Menu and select the 'Run' option. Under
		Windows NT/2000/XP/7/8/10, type 'cmd.exe' (no quotes) in the dialog box that
		shows up; under Windows 95/98/Me, type 'command.com' instead. If
		necessary, change to the proper drive first by typing 'D:' (where 'D' is
		the drive ScummVM is located). Change to ScummVM's directory by typing
		'cd \your\path\to\scummvm' (substituting the appropriate path) and then
		type 'scummvm'.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		On MacOS X, you can find the error messages by starting Console.app
		(in Utilities within the Applications folder). If you prefer, you can
		also run ScummVM from the terminal. To do this, start Terminal.app
		(also in the Utilities folder), then drag&amp;drop the ScummVM.app
		application onto the Terminal window, remove the space at the end of
		the line and add 'Contents/MacOS/scummvm' (without the quotes). The
		line should look like this: '/Path/to/ScummVM.app/Contents/MacOS/scummvm'.
		Then press return to start ScummVM.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		You can also find messages in the ScummVM log file. The location of this file varies depending on your
		operating system. On recent version of Windows it should be in '%appdata%\ScummVM\Logs\scummvm.log'. On OS X
		the log file is '~/Library/Logs/scummvm.log'. On Linux and other POSIX systems we use the XDG Base Directory
		Specification, so by default the file will be '~/.cache/scummvm/logs/scummvm.log' but its location may vary
		depending on the value of the 'XDG_CACHE_HOME' environment variable.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.messy-colors</href>
      <question>The game colors are messed up.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		This is a known issue when using certain Amiga version datafiles.
		Normally, ScummVM should have detected your game as an "Amiga" version,
		but sometimes this fails for various reasons.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		To fix this, select "Amiga" as a platform in the ScummVM Game Options
		dialog, or use the "--platform=amiga" command line parameter to enable
		Amiga-specific code.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>The subtitles in my non-English game are messed up.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		You are most likely using a game such as Maniac Mansion or Zak McKracken
		if you have this problem. You need to specify the correct language in
		the ScummVM Game Options dialog, or via the "--language" parameter or by
		using the 'language' config file option.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		Consult the
		<ulink url="https://github.com/scummvm/scummvm/blob/master/README">README</ulink>
		or command line help for further information.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.mac-games</href>
      <question>How do I make my Macintosh version of a game work?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		First, if you use a ScummVM version prior to 0.7.0 we strongly recommend you
		to upgrade to the latest version, as we improved support for Macintosh games considerably starting with 0.7.0.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		For newer games ScummVM needs the main data file, usually called
		"&lt;Game&nbsp;Title&gt;&nbsp;Data" (where &lt;Game&nbsp;Title&gt; is
		name of your game, such as "The&nbsp;Dig" or "Sam&nbsp;&amp;&nbsp;Max").
		Some CDs may appear to only contain an application (watch out, it has
		almost the same name as the data file, except that it lacks the " Data"
		at the end). In that case there is still a separate data file but it is
		invisible.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		There also exists a separate <ulink url="http://wiki.scummvm.org/index.php/HOWTO-Mac_Games">tutorial
		</ulink> for setting up Macintosh versions
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		The older games which have LFL files should only need the platform set
		to 'macintosh' to run. See "<xref linkend="question.messy-colors" endterm="question.messy-colors.text"/>" for information on specifying the
		game platform.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href>question.report-bugs</href>
      <question>Reporting Bugs.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		To report a bug, please create a SourceForge account and follow the
		<ulink url="http://bugs.scummvm.org/">bugs</ulink>
		link from our homepage. Please make sure the bug is reproducible, and
		still exists in the latest daily build/current repository version. Also check the
		<ulink url="/compatibility/">compatibility listing</ulink> for that game to ensure
		the issue is not already known. In your bugreport please provide the following
		information:
		</simpara>
		<itemizedlist>
		<listitem><simpara>ScummVM version (PLEASE test the latest daily build/current repository)</simpara></listitem>
		<listitem><simpara>Bug details, including instructions on reproducing it</simpara></listitem>
		<listitem><simpara>Language of game (English, German, ...)</simpara></listitem>
		<listitem><simpara>Version of game (talkie, floppy, ...)</simpara></listitem>
		<listitem><simpara>Platform and Compiler (Win32, Linux, MacOS, ...)</simpara></listitem>
		<listitem><simpara>Attach a save game if possible</simpara></listitem>
		<listitem><simpara>If this bug only occurred recently, please note the last
			version without the bug, and the first version including
			the bug. That way we can fix it quicker by looking at the
			changes made.</simpara></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>I downloaded the Broken Sword packs from your site but the game won't run.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		These are not full games but reencoded cutscene (video) packs. To run the games you
		still need the original disks. Originally cutscenes were encoded in a proprietary
		format but Revolution Software kindly permitted us to reencode them into
		DXA and distribute them freely on our site. Note, however, that recent ScummVM versions
		support using the original cutscene files directly. Therefore, you don't have to use the
		ones from our site anymore.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>There are no graphics in the Broken Sword I intro.</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Be patient. There are about 12 seconds of speech only and eventually the Revolution logo
		will appear.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>I get "WARNING: Unable to open configuration file C:\windows\scummvm.ini!"</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Make sure you have enough permissions to write in c:\windows directory. Also note that this warning the
		first time you run ScummVM, since the file does not exist yet then.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>I get "Failed to save game state to file: xxx"</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		Check savepath in Options-&gt;Paths-&gt;Save Path. That should point to writable directory.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>ScummVM starts, but all I get is a transparent window!</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		This problem has been reported to happen under Windows in some cases. Check
		that you have the latest drivers for your graphics card. If that does not
		help, try setting the <envar>SDL_VIDEODRIVER</envar> environment variable to
		"windib" and try again.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		Apparently other applications have had the same problem, because the release
		notes for SDL 1.2.10 (May 17, 2006) contained the following note:
		</simpara>
		<blockquote>
		<simpara>
		The "windib" video driver is the default now, to prevent problems with
		certain laptops, 64-bit Windows, and Windows Vista. The DirectX driver
		is still available, and can be selected by setting the environment
		variable <envar>SDL_VIDEODRIVER</envar> to "directx".
		</simpara>
		</blockquote>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>ScummVM runs, but sound is stuttering and/or garbled!</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		This problem has been reported to happen under Windows in some cases. Check
		that you have the latest drivers for your sound card. If that does not help,
		try setting the <envar>SDL_AUDIODRIVER</envar> environment variable to "waveout"
		and try again.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		Note using the "waveout" SDL audio driver causes an increased delay in sound,
		especially under Windows Vista and later versions.
		</simpara>
		</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>How do I set an environment variable?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		That depends on what operating system and/or command shell you are using.
		Under Windows, you could try creating a file called
		<command moreinfo="none">scummvm.bat</command> in the same folder as
		<command moreinfo="none">scummvm.exe</command>. Open this file in your favorite text
		editor and put something like this in it:
		</simpara>
		<blockquote>
		<programlisting format="linespecific">@echo off
set SDL_VIDEODRIVER=windib
set SDL_AUDIODRIVER=waveout
scummvm.exe %1 %2 %3 %4 %5 %6 %7 %8 %9</programlisting>
		</blockquote>
		<simpara>
		You should now be able to run ScummVM by double-clicking on this batch file,
		instead of the ScummVM executable.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		On more recent versions of Windows, you can also set an environment variable
		permanently, and for all applications, through the control panel.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>ScummVM starts somewhere in the middle of my two Xinerama monitors in fullscreen mode. Help!</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		In fact, this is SDL problem. SDL does by default has xinerama support
		enabled. Set the <envar>SDL_VIDEO_FULLSCREEN_HEAD</envar>
		environment variable to "1" to start ScummVM (and other SDL applications) in
		fullscreen on only one monitor. If this does not work make sure your SDL
		library does have Xinerama support compiled in.
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Features</title>
    <entry>
      <href/>
      <question>Will you add support for zip archives?</question>
      <answer>
		<simpara>
		We will not do it. There are two main reasons for that. First, we believe that it
		would ease illegal distribution of games. Second, we already support compression
		of sound &amp; speech in most larger titles, and use specially designed algorithms
		like MP3, Ogg and FLAC, so you can already reduce the size of the data files.
		</simpara>
		<simpara>
		We as a team already discussed that question. We can't absolutely exclude
		the possibility of changing our mind one day in the future, but for now, we
		have no intentions to do so, hence please don't ask us about it!
		</simpara>
	</answer>
    </entry>
  </section>
</faq>
