<NAME>Curse of Monkey Island - Known issues</NAME>
<DESC>This is a list of current issues that need in SCUMM V8 support</DESC>
<BODY>

<div align="center"><b>Status: Part 1/2/4/5/6 fully playable, part 3 playable with gameplay glitches</b></div>
<ul>
<li>Generic:
	<ul>
		<li>Lack of actorHit opcode breaks collision detection in ship-to-ship combat. Right now we always return 1.
		This causes you to hit yourself in in ship-to-ship combat (but the script still thinks you have won :).
		<li>Guybrush seems to walk down from the sky when entering the Canibal Village for the first time. This is because roomobj-53-873 calls a different script on the first entry, which runs a putActorAtObject opcode before loading the room. 
		<li>Make the in-game options / save-load dialogs work.
		<li>Voice and Music bundles aren't closed before the CD change dialog making it impossible to unmount a CD
		<li>strings that contain PU_M, EC_, SA_, or BT_ should not reach playBundleSound() as they don't
		have audio equivalents.
	</ul>
<li>Sound:
	<ul>
		<li>The sound que fills up, resulting in a spew of warnings. This should never fill up anyway, so it's a bug.
		Easy way to reproduce (although it happens everywhere), start ComI with -d0 -b605, hit ctrl-g... eventually
		things will get spammy.
		<li>Misimplementation of imGetMusicPosition kernel function breaks song sync in Part 3 intro
	</ul>
<li>Graphics:
	<ul>
		<li>Some text does not undraw correctly, again leaving behind artifacts (eg, conversation text, credits)
		<li>Masking artifacts. See many animations, eg during insult sword fighting
	</ul>
<li>Actor:
	<ul>
		<li>o8_getActorChore still seems to be returning dodgy results
		<li>setActorChoreLimbFrame isn't quite correct, eg Wallys animation after throwing the hook will show a few phantom
		frames of his 'throw hook' and 'standing at cannon' animation
		<li>Lack of MouthSync and MusicMouthSync stuff causes odd actor speech animations 
		(CVS hacked to generate random values... it's wrong, it's not synced, but it look better than nothing)
		<li>Dinghy dog shrinks size after he bites you, use boot param 1000 to test
	</ul>
</ul>

</BODY>
