<NAME>Curse of Monkey Island - Known issues</NAME>
<DESC>This is a list of current issues that need in SCUMM V8 support</DESC>
<BODY>
                <style>
                        h2 {
                                margin-bottom: 0px;
                        }
                        h3 {
                                margin-bottom: 0px;
                        }

                        ul {
                                padding-bottom: 10px;
                        }
                </style>
<ul>
<li>Generic:
	<ul>
		<li>No SMUSH Audio: aquadran is working on this one
		<li>Something is wrong with our flObject 
implementation. See the conversation bug below. This problem also 
causes a crash when bringing up the inventory after taking all the 
items in the Snake in Part II (object 116, loaded and locked in 
bootscript)
	</ul>
<li>Inventory:
	<ul>
		<li>Click on an object in the inventory. Right click to 'drop it'.. now click on any blank space in the inventory. B00M!
	</ul>
<li> Conversation:
	<ul>
		<li>An flobject loading error seems to cause frequent crashes in later conversations.
		    Specifically the object never seems to be loaded in some sequences. Eg, talking to the
		    voodoo lady - during the first conversation, the object (188/189) is loaded. But after
		    the cutscene where Guybrush finds Elaine stolen, on returning the object is unloaded
		    and after the automated conversation the game will crash because it is unlocatable.
		    <b>This one is important, it's the main thing preventing people from progressing further
		    in Part II (you need to complete the Voodoo Lady conversation</b>
			

		<li>Frequently conversations will crash with a "Too Many Verbs" error. Easiest step to
	  	    reproduce is to save a game before talking to somebody.. if talking to them the first
		    time doesn't trigger it, the save probably will. NOTE: This does not seem to happen to
		    characters who say something before the conversation menu comes up - eg, Wally. Try
		    talking to Murray after blowing the ships away. (HACK IN CVS)
	</ul>
<li>Actor:
	<ul>
		<li>The CHORE opcode still seems to be returning dodgy results
		<li>Lack of MouthSync stuff causes odd actor speech animations
		<li>Lack of MusicMouthSync will stop entry into Part 3 (hang during song sequence)
		<li>No ScaleSlot implementation means bad scaling
	</ul>
</ul>

</BODY>
