<NAME>Curse of Monkey Island - Known issues</NAME>
<DESC>This is a list of current issues that need in SCUMM V8 support</DESC>
<BODY>
	<style>
		h2 {
			margin-bottom: 0px;
		}
		h3 {
			margin-bottom: 0px;
		}

		ul {
			padding-bottom: 10px;
		}
	</style>
<center><b>Status: Part 1/2 fully playable, part 3 playable with graphical glitches if ship-to-ship combat is cheated past</b></center>
<ul>
<li>Generic:
	<ul>
		<li>AKOS crash leaving the crash site on Blood Island (scummvm -d0 -b600)
		<li>Lack of actorHit opcode makes entering swordfighting during ship-to-ship oombat impossible without using shift-v cheat
		<li>Cannot fire cannons in ship-to-ship combat
	</ul>
<li>Sound:
	<ul>
		<li>No SMUSH Audio: aquadran is working on this one
		<li>Voices 'pop'
		<li>Occasional crashes from 'sound que buffer overflow' (hard to reproduce)
		<li>Lack of imGetMusicPosition kernel function breaks song sync in Part 3 intro
	</ul>
<li>Graphics:
	<ul>
		<li>Some text does not undraw correctly, again leaving behind artifacts
		<li>Masking artifacts. See many animations, eg during insult sword fighting
	</ul>
<li>Conversation:
	<ul>
		<li>Verbs do not redraw correctly on scrolling, specifically during Insult Sword Fighting (Part 3). Makes it hard to
complete without much squinting
	</ul>
<li>Inventory:
	<ul>
		<li>Upon combining two items in such a way as to reduce a two-page inventory to a one-page, trying to select the last 
item will actually return the second-last item
	</ul>
<li>Actor:
	<ul>
		<li>The CHORE opcode still seems to be returning dodgy results
		<li>setActorChoreLimbFrame isn't quite correct, eg Wallys animation after throwing the hook will show a few phantom
frames of his 'throw hook' and 'standing at cannon' animation
		<li>Lack of MouthSync and MuaicMouthSync stuff causes odd actor speech animations
		<li>Actor 1 (Guybrush) occasionally gets stuck (e.g. after taking Wally's fake hook). Can work-around with console
command "actor 1 ignoreboxes 1"
	</ul>
</ul>

</BODY>
