<NAME>Mac CD ScummVM HOWTO</NAME>
<DESC>This page describes how to copy files from Mac LEC game releases and prepare them for ScummVM.</DESC>
<BODY>

<h1>Mac CD ScummVM HOWTO</h1>

<h2>Introduction:</h2>

<p>This is a rough description of how to use your Macintosh CD
version of a classic LucasArts game with ScummVM on Win32. Following
procedure describes how to do it with "Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road
Macintosh CD-ROM" on Windows 2000 Professional. Your mileage may 
vary with other titles or versions of Windows.</p>

<h2>Tools:</h2>

<p>You will need the "Windows Installer" from the 
<a href="http://scummvm.sourceforge.net/downloads.php">download page</a>.
If you're using ScummVM version prior to 0.7.0 you additionally will need
"ScummVM Tools Windows Installer" from same URL.
To copy the game data file from the CD to your hard disc, you will
need 
<a href="http://gamma.nic.fi/~lpesonen/HFVExplorer/">HFVExplorer</a>. Make
sure you get the "HFV Explorer installer" rather than the zip
file.</p>

<p>You should be running as Administrator to install all of the
tools. Everything else should work as a normal user. Run the
ScummVM installers and allow them to install to the default
location (C:\ScummVM). Don't worry about overwriting files. Run the
HFVExplorer installer and allow it to use its defaults.</p>

<h2>Copying the game data file:</h2>

<p>Start up HFVExplorer; if you don't have a shortcut for it, find
it in "c:\program&nbsp;files\HFVExplorer". It should open the HFS
(Macintosh filesystem) CD-ROM automatically when you insert the
disc. Make sure HFVExplorer is displaying hidden files: Select
View-&gt;Options and enable "Show invisible Mac files" on the "File
attributes" tab.</p>

<p>Now, look for the data file in the right pane. It will probably
end with the word "Data" and will be the largest file on the
volume. For instance, it is called "Sam &amp; Max Data" on the "Sam
&amp; Max" CD-ROM. Select the data file and copy it (use Ctrl+C or
Edit-&gt;Copy). In the left HFVExplorer pane, navigate to the
directory where you want the game to reside on your hard disc. We
recommend selecting drive C: and creating a new folder called
"SamNMax" or a name that better reflects your particular game.</p>

<p>Paste the data file (with Ctrl+V or Edit-&gt;Paste) and allow
HFVExplorer to choose the copy mode. Now, wait while the program
copies several hundred megabytes from the CD. When the file is
copied, close HFVExplorer.</p>

<h2>Running rescumm:</h2>

<p><b>NOTE:</b> If you are using ScummVM version 0.7.0 and
above, you don't need this. Just point ScummVM to folder where
you copied the Data file. <small>(Hint: If you're using older
version we strongly recommend to upgrade)</small></p>

<p>Open a command prompt window and change the directory to your
newly created folder. Then, run rescumm on the data file to extract
its contents. For example, type the following for Sam &amp; Max,
making sure you use double quotes around the data filename:</p>
<pre>
cd c:\SamNMax
c:\scummvm\rescumm "Sam &amp; Max Data"

</pre>

<p>Once the several files are successfully extracted, you can
delete the data file. Now, you can fire up ScummVM and add the new
game to play it. The ScummVM documentation (README) describes
ScummVM and rescumm usage in detail. If you have any questions,
look at the <a href="/faq.php">ScummVM FAQ</a>,
the <a href="/documentation.php">ScummVM Documentation</a>, and the
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/forum/?group_id=37116">forums</a>.</p>

<h2>Related Information:</h2>

<p>If you are using ScummVM on MacOS X, you may find
<a href="http://www.ps2cheats.com/randomstuff/scumm/">How to Rescumm for Dummies!</a> useful.</p>
<p><br />
<br />
Based on document Copyright &copy; 2004 Jonathan Rogers</p>

</BODY>