<NAME>ScummVM current areas of focus</NAME>
<DESC>This page is the current TODO list for ScummVM.</DESC>
<BODY>
	<h1>ScummVM current areas of focus</h1>
	
	<h2>Introduction</h2>
	<p>
		If you want to dig in, this is the place to find out what we're
		currently working on (or hoping somebody will pick it up for us,
		you never know). This is the stuff where you might make the most
		useful contribution, right now. Note that this is never complete,
		and may be partially outdated, so just because you don't see it
		here doesn't mean it is not important.
	</p>
	<p>Before you start work on something, you might want to talk to
		somebody from the team. This will help us to prevent double work,
		i.e. several people working on the same stuff at once without
		knowing about each other.
	</p>
	<p>
		Finally, always make sure to check out our <a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?atid=418820&group_id=37116&func=browse">bug tracker</a>
		and our <a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?atid=418823&group_id=37116&func=browse">feature request tracker</a>
		for things that need work.
	</p>
	
	<h2>Future goals</h2>
	<p>Here is a list of things we plan to do for the future. Note that we don't promise to do any of these, nor when we will do them. It's just a list
	of what we hope to be able to do one day.</p>
	<ul>
	<li>Music and sound effects in Indy3Ega, Indy3Vga, LoomEga, MonkeyEga and MonkeyVga</li>
	<li>Proper Full Throttle support</li>
	<li>Curse of Monkey Island support (we already have that partially in latest CVS!)</li>
	<li>Maniac Mansion support</li>
	<li>Zak McKracken (non-FmTowns) support</li>
	<li>Proper LoomEga support</li>
	<li>Proper Indy3Ega support</li>
	</ul>

	<h3>General</h3>
	<ul>
		<li><p><b>Rewrite sound code so that the Adlib and MIDI encoders can be active at the same time.</b></p>
		<ul>
			<li>This will help in a few cases where games have a few tracks only available in Adlib format</li>
			<li>Necessary if we want to allow users to switch between different games at runtime</li>
		</ul>
		</li>
		<li><p>Make it possible to restart (scumm) games</p></li>
		<li><p>Allow the user to choose between multiple video drivers at startup when multiple choices are possible.
		E.g. between SDL vs. SDL_gl. Just like one can choose a midi driver. Currently one has to recompile for this.</p></li>
		<li><p>Add a "help" ingame dialog which lists key shortcuts etc.</p></li>
		<li><p>Add long style command line arguments that work in a portable manner across many systems ie --foo-bar as we are quickly running out of single letters to use for arguments, and they make more sense</p></li>
	</ul>
	<h3>New GUI</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>Improve the launcher</li>
		<li>Add tab support (i.e. allow multiple panes in one dialog)</li>
		<li>Implement the global preferences dialog (it is already there but nothing is wired)</li>
		<li><i>Ask: Fingolfin, Ender</i></li>
	</ul>
	<h3>Specific games</h3>
	<ul>
		<li><h4>The DIG</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Some in-game music and sound issues</li>
			<li><i>Ask: Ender</i></li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Monkey1EGA</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Fix music support, add sound support</li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Monkey1VGA</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Fix music support, add sound support</li>
			<li><i>Ask: MadMoose, Fingolfin</i></li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Zak256</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Incomplete sound effect support</li>
			<li>Several small bugs (see bug list)</li>
			<li><i>Ask: Ender</i></li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Full Throttle</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>INSANE supported required</li>
			<li><i>Ask: Ender, aquadran</i></li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade EGA</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Add music and sound support</li>
			<li>Fix grail diary and biplane manual not been drawn correctly</li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Fix music support, add sound support</li>
			<li>Correct random walkbox issues</li>
			<li><i>Ask: Ender</i></li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Loom EGA</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Add music and sound support</li>
			<li>Fix subtitles not been shown in correct color and place</li>
			<li>Fix crash when picking up distaff</li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Passport to Adventure</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Fix music support and add sound support</li>
			<li>Fix subtitles not been shown in indy3 demo</li>
		</ul>
		<li><h4>The Curse of Monkey Island</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>See <a href="../documentation.php?view=comi">here</a> for a list.
		</ul>
		<li><h4>Simon the Sorcerer 1 & 2</h4>
		<ul>
			<li>Add proper tranparency support</li>
			<li>Add XMI music support for simon2dos/talkie</li>
			<li>Add proper music support for Simon the Sorcerer 2</li>
			<li>Check <a href="http://members.optusnet.com.au/wormmon/simon.html">Simon issues</a> for list of other bugs</li>
			<li><i>Ask: olki, Kirben</i></li>
		</ul>
	</ul>
</BODY>
